两周前
Two weeks ago,
一个无形的穹顶坠落在小镇上方
an invisible dome crashed down on Chester's Mill,
使我们与外部世界隔绝
cutting us off from the rest of the world.
穹顶为何降落在此或者隐藏着什么奥秘
Why the dome is here or what mysteries lie ahead,
我们仍然不知道
we still don't know.
它每天考验着我们的极限
Every day it tests our limits,
激发了我们内心至善至恶的一面
bringing out the best and the worst in us.
有人说我们将永远被困在这里
Some say we'll be stuck here forever,
但我们永远不会放弃寻找出路
but we will never stop fighting to find a way out.
我正在接收电子邮件
I'm getting e-mail.
信号变得越来越强烈
Signal's getting stronger.
信号来源于这儿
It's coming from here.
詹姆斯 我希望你知道
James, I expect you know,
我还活着
that I'm alive.
去找莱尔乔姆利
Talk to Lyle Chumley.
不，不，快，快点
No, no, no. Come on, come on, come on.
她快被湖水淹死了
She was drowning in the lake.
她莫名其妙出现
She just appeared.
我不知道她从哪里冒出来的
I have no idea where she came from.
你25年前曾许诺
You made a promise 25 years ago
会确保我们埋葬的不会重见天日
to make sure that what we buried stayed buried.
看起来像是安琪在凶手身上留下了伤痕
Looks like Angie got a piece of whoever did this to her.
这是一只手的指尖
Those are the fingertips of a hand--
一只大手
a big hand.
一只男人的手
A man's.
88年夏天
"Summer '88."
莱尔 山姆和波林
"Lyle, Sam and Pauline."
什么
What?
这上面有什么
What is it?
是 我
It's... me.
没有足够的食物支持我们的那一天就要到来了
Day's coming when there won't be enough food to sustain us.
也许我们有必要
It may become necessary--
减少人口数量了
to thin the herd.
这就是个人口普查 来帮你决定谁生谁死
this is a census, to help you decide who lives and who dies.
上午好
Good morning.
我不知道它多有效
I'm not sure how good it is.
它会有效的 只要你用我们的普查
It is if you're using the census
来解决人口问题
to address our population problem.
嗯 我需要了解我们目前的情况
Well, got to see where we stand.
好吧 我们了解我们的情况
Well, we know where we stand.
我们需要的是健康 有实用技能
We need people who are healthy, with practical skills,
可以多付出少索取的人
who give more than they take.
所以 下一个是谁呢
So, who's next?
爱丽丝
Alice.
她是穹顶之下的第一个宝宝
She was the first dome baby.
她母亲哈丽特 是主日学校的老师
Her mother's Harriet-- she teaches Sunday school.
哈丽特还能做什么
What else does Harriet do?
就这样
That's it.
她是一个 单身妈妈
She's a... single mother,
是个有信仰的女人
a woman of faith.
吉姆 我们的粮食供应正在缩减
Jim, our food supplies are dwindling.
我们不能任由感情支配我们的行动
We can't let these emotions dictate.
这没那么简单
It won't be easy...
听着 我和这些人一起长大
Listen, I grew up with these people.
我被选中领导大家
I was chosen to lead them.
我不会摇晃这棵大树 除非我已经明白
I'm not gonna shake the tree until I'm sure
谁可以承受自己的分量
who can carry their own weight...
而谁不可以
and who can't.
那你怎么才能确认呢
But how will you be sure?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许穹顶会指引我
Maybe the dome will guide me.
这是一个开始
That's a start.
你要去哪儿
What are you up to?
我要去学校
I'm headed to the school.
我们的风车发电项目真的有进展了
Our windmill power project is really coming along.
听着 丽贝卡
Listen, Rebecca...
我们会度过难关的
we're gonna get through this.
只要你带领我们
As long as you're leading us.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
不
No.
根据我们在安吉的指甲里发现的东西
Did Phil I.D. Angie's killer
菲尔查到杀死她的凶手了吗
from the stuff we found under her fingernails?
这是一个死胡同 没有办法比对DNA
That's a dead end-- there's no way to run the DNA.
更何况在磁化事件后一半的镇民都可能有划痕
And half the town probably has scratches after the magnetization.
丽贝卡 佩恩认为切斯特镇
Rebecca Pine thinks Chester's Mill
无法自给自足多久了
can't sustain itself for much longer,
她和吉姆想利用人口普查
and she and Jim want to use the census
来决定谁生谁死
to decide who lives and who doesn't.
我知道 这听起来很疯狂
I know. It sounds crazy.
不 老吉姆总是有上帝情结
No. Big Jim's always had a God complex.
我知道他们有一个计划 我们需要弄明白那是什么计划
I know they have a plan; we need to find out what it is.
我们
We?
我需要你的帮助
I could use the help.
芭比站在哪边呢
Where does Barbie stand on all this?
在吉姆一边
On Jim's side.
吉姆
Jim.
我们需要谈谈你灭绝计划
We need to talk about your extermination plan.
-那是减少人口的方法 -好吧 随便什么
- Reduction option. - Okay, whatever.
你看 我知道我们需要做最坏的打算 好吗
Look, I know that we need to prepare for the worst, okay?
但如果那一天真的发生了 我需要清楚
But if that day happens, I want to be clear--
除非大家都同意否则不能有任何行动
no one acts unless we both agree.
听着 芭比
Listen, Barbie, I don't
我和你一样不希望见到这一天
want that day to get here any more than you do.
没有你的话 切斯特镇
Look, Chester's Mill couldn't have survived
都不会安然度过过去的几天
the past few days without you--
磁场问题 农作物 血雨
the magnets, the crops, the rain.
如果我们需要采取下一步动作
If we need to take that next step,
我们会一起行动的
we do it together.
哈丽特
Harriet.
这里没有那么多人
There's so many people here.
这让我觉得爱丽丝有一个大家庭
It makes me feel like Alice has a family.
是的 没错
Well, that's right.
我们都是一家人
One big family.
嘿 有你照顾大家真是太幸运了 对吧 芭比
Hey, we're so lucky to have you take care of us. Right, Barbie?
没错
That's right.
如果这个地方的食物供应不足
If this place runs out of food,
希望我们不会变成大家的公愤吧
let's hope that we're not on the menu.
怎么会这样
How can this be?
年鉴可不会说谎
Yearbooks don't lie.
这是25年前的
It's from 25 years ago.
嘿 这是你的私事
Hey, this is kind of personal,
-但你在这上面放探针标记了吗 -乔 拜托
- but do you have probe marks? - Joe, please.
你的高等生物理论还是留着去
Save your theory on intelligent life-forms of the universe
演讲吧
for a TED talk.
这能解释她失忆 和她几十年来都没有
Explain her memory loss, and the fact that
变老的原因
she hasn't aged in decades.
可能是穹顶派她来的呢
Maybe the dome sent her.
就像我妈一样
It sent my mom.
不是 梅兰妮是个人
No, Melanie's a person.
-穹顶派来的都是幻象 但我们是摸不着的 -好吧
- The dome sent an avatar; you can't grab an avatar. - Okay,
不管她到底是什么 我们还是不要乱碰为好
whatever she is, let's not manhandle her.
既然她不可能是梅兰妮 克鲁斯
And since there's no way she's actually Melanie Cross,
那么我们就不该那样子称呼她
then we probably shouldn't call her that.
那我们该叫她什么
Then what should we call her?
我应该知道我的名字是什么的
I should know what my name is.
但我却不知道
But I don't.
我们可以让他知道
We should show him.
呃 不行 他最不想听到的估计
Uh, yeah, no, the last thing he wants to hear
就是你发现了一口1988年的不老泉
is that you found the fountain of youth in 1988.
还穿着和昨天一样的衣服呢
Rockin' the same clothes as yesterday.
太忙了 所以昨晚没回家吗
Too busy to come home last night?
是啊 茱莉亚在这里吗
Yeah. Is Julia here?
不在 她留了字条说一会儿就回来
No. She left a note saying she'll be back later.
你们几个那么早起床干嘛
What are you guys doing up so early?
-我们要跟茱莉亚聊聊 -我们收到了电子邮件
- We need to talk to Julia... - Uh, we got e-mails.
你们什么时候收到了电子邮件
You got e-mails when?
就昨天
Yesterday.
你们居然现在才告诉我
And you're just telling me about this now?
我们都收到了邮件 然后突然就没信号了
We all got e-mails, until the signal was blocked.
然后这就突然出现了
And this popped up.
该页面无法打开
"This page can't be displayed."
你觉得是军队屏蔽了我们的信号 还是
You think the military's blocking us, or...?
这不是正常的网页
That's not the standard response.
如果信号能够回来 我们就可以
We get that signal back, we can communicate
跟外界联系了
with the outside world.
嘿 带我去你们连接上信号的地方
Hey, I want you to take me to where this came through.
恶魔将驱汝入狱
The devil shall cast some of you into prison,
纵汝垂死挣扎
that ye may be tried;
汝将受十日磨难
ye shall have tribulation ten days:
心存不死之念
be thou faithful unto death,
汝将重获生存之冠
and I will give you a crown of life.
站起来 莱尔
On your feet, Lyle.
你是来放我出去的吗
You came to set me free.
我妈说你知道原因 所以我就来找你了
My mother said you had answers; I want them.
我不仅可以告诉你
I can do better than tell you.
我
I...
我还可以带你去看
I can show you.
让我出去
Let me out.
把这个拷上
Put these on.
你怎么可以这样呢
O ye of little faith.
你绑架了丽贝卡 还企图杀了她
You kidnapped Rebecca and you tried to kill her.
她妨碍到
She was standing...
我的开心时光了
in the way of the Rapture.
如果我放你出来
If I'm gonna break you out,
至少得把你的双手铐住
I want your hands together.
就当是在祈祷吧
Think of it as a prayer.
-多谢你过来 -小猪怎么样
- Thanks for coming over. - How's the piglet?
我觉得应该是流感
I think it's a flu.
很抱歉 太迟了
I'm sorry. It's too late.
我比较担心其他的几只
I'm worried about the others.
她是一头新生猪 其他的都很健壮
She was a newborn. The others are strong.
就算是流感 他们也能熬过去的
If it's a flu, they'll fight it.
你知道 人也有可能会被感染的
You know,people can catch this, too.
你没事吧
Are you feeling all right?
我没事 贝斯也没事
I'm fine. So is Beth.
我们跟小猪接触的时候都很小心
We've been careful about contact.
很好
Good.
你有手推车吗
Do you have a wheelbarrow?
最好能避免跟病猪接触
No sense touching her more than you have to.
万事皆有因果
Everything happens for a reason.
无线网的信号没了
This Wi-Fi signal's gone.
我们之前来的时候就没有了
It disappeared when we got here.
所以 你是说这里是信号最强的是吗
So, you said this is where it was strongest, right here?
是的 这个柜子也很诡异
Yep. Because not enough's creepy about that locker.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
我要去找东西撬开它看看里面有什么
I'm gonna have to go find something to pry this open with.
翻译：小泥  琪琪  winni  慕斯  Bezero  柯小南
呃 里面空空如也
Uh, there's nothing in there.
你是怎么知道的 这个柜子被上锁了
But you don't know that-- it's locked.
校对：Elsa  Bezero  VeraS  慕斯
你怎么知道密码的
How do you know that combination?
我觉得这个柜子以前是我用的
I think this was my locker...
在1988年
in 1988.
后期：hhjie     时间轴：阿黎     总监：柯小南
什么
What?
穹顶之下
第二季  第四集
等等 这是在开玩笑吗
Okay, I-is this some kind of joke?
是老天开的玩笑
Played on us by the universe.
像她吧
Looks like her, huh?
讲不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
难道穹顶就说得通了吗
And the dome does?
我的意思是 你都可以做照片里这个女孩的女儿了
I mean, you could be this girl's daughter.
芭比
Barbie...
你知道那种一直被当做外人的感觉吗
you know what it's like to be a stranger here.
我不想再这样下去了
I don't want to be one anymore.
我不确定我能不能帮到你
I'm not sure I can help you with that.
为什么不呢
Why not?
信号已经没了
The signal's gone.
就来帮我们查清楚她到底是谁吧
Help us figure out who she really is.
走吧
Let's go.
丽贝卡喜欢把工作带回家
Rebecca likes to take her work home with her.
或者是不想在学校被人看到她的工作
Or doesn't want to be seen doing it at school.
她去过淤泥很多的地方
She's been somewhere with a lot of muck.
早饭吃鸡蛋 晚饭吃血样
Eggs for breakfast, blood samples for dinner?
不管她在干什么 她都做了防范措施
Whatever she's doing, she's taking precautions.
是的 她还有一本记录了
Yeah. She's got a calendar
食物保质期和资源殆尽日期的备忘录
of when we run out of food and resources.
她真的觉得世界末日到了
She really does think it's the end of days.
我们的科学老师居然加入了教会 真是稀奇
Our science teacher in prayer group. That's new.
好吧 她确实对上帝创造的物种
Well, she does have an interest
很感兴趣啊 猪
in one of God's creatures, pigs.
血样 兽医书
Blood work, vet books,
门口擦鞋垫上的淤泥
mud on the doormat.
在这附近有养猪的农场寥寥无几
There are a few farms around here with pigs.
我们去看看她最近是不是去过
Let's see if she paid a visit to any of them recently.
丽贝卡
Rebecca?
有人吗
Hello?
丽贝卡
Rebecca?
你在研究风车发电吗
You working on the windmills?
丽贝卡
Rebecca?
我们真的要在茱莉亚的新闻办公室用缩微胶卷吗
We're supposed to use microfilm in Julia's newspaper office?
没搞错吧 这是石器时代研究事物的方法啊
Seriously? This is how they found things in the Stone Age.
对啊 我们不能直接搜索梅兰妮的名字吗
Yeah, we can't search by Melanie's name?
不能 只能一个个看下去
No. You just got to scroll and look.
我怀念网络 怀念我的手机
I miss the Internet, I miss my cell phone,
怀念发短信 怀念寿司
I miss texting, I miss sushi.
记录数据库什么都没查到
Well, the Hall of Records turned up nothing, okay?
这是最后一个我能想到的
This is the last place that I can think to look...
能找东西的地方了
for whatever it is that we might find.
梅兰妮没有出现在1987年或是1989年的年鉴里
Melanie wasn't in the '87 or '89 yearbooks.
也许独立报社在1988年报道过他们家搬到
Maybe The Independent ran an article about why her family
切斯特磨坊镇来的原因
came to Chester's Mill in 1988.
或是为什么她离开了
Or why she left.
在这连西红柿突破重量
In a town where Betsy Van Needles' record-breaking tomato
都能上头条的镇子上
makes the front page,
我得说 我们干得不错
I'd say we have a pretty good shot.
伙计们 快看
Guys, look.
梅兰妮 克鲁斯 神秘失踪 未被寻回
Melanie Cross went missing and was never found.
那家人不久前
The family moved "To
刚从齐尼思搬到切斯特镇
Chester's Mill from Zenith a short time ago."
齐尼思
Zenith?
我也是从那个镇出来的
That's the same town that I'm from.
我就说 我看你面熟
I thought you looked familiar.
梅兰妮一家住在古橡城24号
Melanie's family lived at 24 Old Oak Drive.
如果她在柜子前面的时候
If she remembered the combo
能想起来柜子密码组合的话 那么
when she stood in front of her locker, then...
你是说 如果我们带她回家的话 她会想起更多事情
You think she'll remember more if we take her to the house?
不
No.
不 她想不起来的 因为她不是 她不是梅兰妮 克鲁斯
No, she won't. Because she's not... she's not Melanie Cross.
这是不可能的
There's just no way.
我想去那里
I want to go there.
我必须得去
I have to.
好吧
All right.
那我们闯入那栋房子的时候
What do we say when we barge in on the family
怎么跟现在住在那里的家庭解释呢
that lives there now?
让我来处理
You let me handle that.
告诉我 我妈现在还活着吗
Talk to me. Tell me how my mother's still alive.
我们不是计划好了吗 切断制动管路
We had a plan: severed brake lines,
盗出尸体 傻瓜牧师考金斯 他
pilfered corpses, that idiot Reverend Coggins, he...
愿上帝安息
God rest his soul.
我妈妈造成自杀的假象 你帮了她
My mother faked her suicide, and you helped her?
我很爱她 詹姆斯 依然如故
I loved her very much, James, I still do.
她抛弃了我
She abandoned me.
那是为了保护你 她知道穹顶要降临了
To protect you. She knew the dome was coming.
那些画里的粉色星星
The pink stars in the paintings?
她要在被带走前逃出去
She had to get out before she was taken out.
什么意思
What does that mean?
你爸对她有别的计划
Your father had other plans for her.
他不知道她还活着吗
He has no idea that she's still alive?
不知道
No.
那山姆呢
What about Sam?
波林只相信让我帮她逃出
Pauline only trusted me to help her escape.
什么样的母亲会自己离开让自己的儿子留在这个地狱里
What kind of a mother leaves her son behind in this hell?
我觉得她认为 穹顶会跟着她而放过你
I think she thought the dome would follow her and spare you.
我还要去参加她的葬礼
I had to go to her funeral.
她把我留在这儿 是她让我变成大吉姆·兰尼
She left me here. She left me to turn into Big Jim Rennie.
听着 你妈妈信任我
Look, your mother trusts me.
这九年来波林都是这么和我联系的
For nine years that's how Pauline stayed in touch.
用明信片
With postcards?
是啊
Yeah.
这都是从不同地方寄来的
They're from all different places,
但上面什么都没有写
but there's nothing on 'em.
有啊
Yeah, there is.
她做了这些东西 你把它们翻过来
She made those. Turn 'em over.
她的画
Her paintings.
看着熟悉吗
Do those look familiar?
这都是自从穹顶降临以来发生的事
This is all the stuff that happened since the dome came down.
那个蛋 那些蝴蝶 还有红雨
The egg, the butterflies, the red rain.
如果她在穹顶之外 她怎么可能知道
If she's out there, how could she possibly know
穹顶这下面发生了什么
what's going on under here?
波林看到的远不止粉色星星
Pauline saw a lot more than pink stars.
我没看见什么风车
I don't see any windmills.
你偷了我的卡
You stole my card,
还向我说谎
lied to me.
你想做什么呢 丽贝卡
What are you doing, Rebecca?
我在想办法
I'm finding a way.
当穹顶刚刚降临的时候 我开始拜访农场
When the dome first came down, I started visiting farms,
观察庄稼和牲畜
monitoring crops and livestock.
汤姆 蒂尔登 有一头病猪
Tom Tilden had a sick pig.
是流感
The flu.
鸡蛋里有什么 丽贝卡
What's inside the eggs, Rebecca?
你说你会全力拯救小镇
You said you'd do what it takes to save this town.
鸡蛋里的东西就是你的法宝
What's inside those eggs is how you're gonna do it.
有人吗
Hello?
他们前门没锁
They left the front door unlocked.
可能在穹顶降临那天去了西湖参加游行
Probably went to the parade in Westlake
被挡在穹顶之外了
and got trapped outside the dome on Dome Day.
真走运
Lucky them.
他们都还没有吃完早饭
They didn't even finish breakfast.
有个孩子不用做完代数作业了
Some kid didn't have to finish his algebra homework
还逃出了这个仓鼠球
and avoided the hamster ball.
真是一箭双雕啊
Double win.
那个看起来眼熟吗
Does it look familiar?
我记不得任何东西了
I don't remember anything.
因为没什么可以想起来的
Because there's nothing to remember.
我只感到悲伤
All I feel is sad.
回到家里但是家人不在身边的感觉糟透了
It sucked having to walk through my house with my family gone.
在安琪过世后
And after Angie...
我很庆幸房子塌了
I'm glad the place fell down.
我该怎么和一个
How am I supposed to compete with a girl
他觉得来自很遥远的外星系的女孩儿竞争呢
he thinks is from a galaxy far, far away?
我肯定他想要帮点忙
I'm sure he's just trying to help.
别指望能消除我的嫉妒和被抛弃的感觉
Don't undermine my feelings of jealousy and abandonment.
但是既然我们都聊到这儿了 你和朱莉娅出什么事儿了
But since we're chatting, what's up with you and Julia?
拜托 你摆出一副 快原谅我 的样子
Come on. You show up with the "Please forgive me" Face.
她在你到这儿之前就离开了
She left before you got there,
她一定不想听你说话
so she didn't want to hear it.
你肯定做了什么超级坏的事
Whatever you did was super bad.
你眉毛刚刚抽搐了
Your eyebrow just twitched.
是啊
Yeah, it did.
我真高兴能和你这样小小地聊一下
I'm really glad we could have this little chat.
芭比 诺尔
Barbie, Nore.
噢 天哪 这是我做的
Oh, my God. I made these.
我曾经看到窗外 发现它们在掉落
I used to look out the window and see them falling.
她看见星星掉落了吗
She saw stars fall?
是粉红色的
They were pink.
是啊 就在那儿
Yeah. Over there.
我还出去找过它们
I went out to find them.
那是我们发现小穹顶的地方
That's where we found the mini-dome.
我们要去那里
We got to go there.
乔 别慌
Joe, slow down.
穹顶不知怎么就出现了
The dome came out of nowhere
就此改变了我们的生活
and changed our lives forever.
安吉被杀了 我可能永远都不会知道答案
Angie was killed-- I might never know why.
这是个机会 让我找寻真相
This is a chance to find an answer
去找到那该死的答案
to find one damn answer
即便不是为了我而找
even if it's not for me.
我觉得我们应该去树林
I think we should look.
好吧 那我们就动身
All right. We go to the woods.
如果一无所获就回家
If we find nothing, we go home.
谢谢
Thank you.
跑了六家农场 一无所获
Six farms and nothing.
还有一家呢
Still one to go.
是啊 可是按照农民们说的
Yeah, but according to the farmers,
瑞贝卡只是在观察牲口和作物
Rebecca was only monitoring livestock and crop yields.
她说人口普查是为了确定粮食存量
She said the point of the town census was to inventory resources.
也许
Maybe...
怎么了
What?
也许她没有谋划什么坏事
Maybe she's not planning anything bad.
不 不 你没听到她的语气
No, no, no. You didn't hear what I heard in her voice.
或是看到她拿酸雨泼莱尔的场景
Or see her douse Lyle with that acid rain.
尽管这也许不是第一次我看走眼
Though it wouldn't be the first time I've misjudged someone.
其实我并不太了解你
I don't really know you.
我在树林里待太久了
Hell, I've been out in the woods for so long,
有时候我甚至都不认得自己了
there are days I don't even know myself.
但我知道我以前遭到过背叛
But I do know that I've been betrayed before.
你想说什么 萨姆
What are you getting at, Sam?
林子大了 什么鸟都有
People are full of surprises.
确实是
They sure are.
你计划了多久了
How long you been planning this?
那些猪我观察了好几周了
I'd been monitoring the pig for weeks.
在家检测血液 观察病毒怎样侵袭细胞
Testing blood at my house to see how the virus affected cells.
那你打算什么时候再告诉我
When were you gonna tell me?
当一切就绪的时候
Once everything was ready.
这就是我为什么要到这里
That's why I needed to get in here,
我要混合猪流感和人的流感病毒
to mix the swine flu with samples of influenza.
几小时后 混合病毒就足够有效
In a few hours, the recombinant virus inside those eggs
能让镇上四分之一的人丧生
will be strong enough to infect one quarter of this town.
你想下毒
You want to release it?
不
No.
我想你去做
I want you to.
你想让我来扮演上帝
You want me to play God?
你说过你想看谁能承受生命之重
You said you wanted to see who could carry their own weight.
这就是方法
This is how.
这不是神学 这是进化学
It's not God-- it's-it's Darwin.
符合适者生存
It's survival of the fittest.
-也就是说 我们自己也可能会中招 -对
- Meaning we're at risk, too. - Yes.
病毒是上天自然选择的最好方式
A virus is nature's way of leveling the playing field.
这想法太疯狂了
This is crazy.
这是上天的仁慈
It's merciful.
7天以后 我们就弹尽粮绝
In seven days, we run out of food.
14天后 人们会饥饿无比
In 14, people will be starving.
21天后 我们会自相残杀
In 21, we'll turn on each other.
现在就是做出行动的最佳时间
The time to act is now.
病毒是怎么进入穹顶的
How'd this virus get inside the dome?
它一直都在 只是一直在休眠
It's always been here, dormant in nature for...
沉睡了数周 数月 也许数年
weeks, months... maybe years.
你是说 穹顶就像孵化器
You mean like an incubator.
是它让着一切发生的
The dome made this happen.
-你说我妈是个预言家 -不 我是说
- You're saying my mom's a prophet? - No, I'm saying
这些事件将我们推向世界末日
that these events brought us closer to the apocalypse,
当生活焚烧地球
when the world's gonna burn with the sacred fires
字幕我们的骨灰就将飘向天堂
and our ashes are gonna float up into the heavens.
那时 我会与波林团聚
That's when I'm gonna be with Pauline again.
这场雨
The rain...
我以为是世界末日的预兆
I thought presaged the end of days,
只是因为那是我收到的最后一张卡片
but that's just 'cause that's the last card I got.
不关它是什么
Well, whatever it was,
瑞贝卡阻止了它真是万幸
it was a good thing that Rebecca stopped it.
嘿 如果她打乱了穹顶的计划
Hey! If she interfered with the dome's plan,
我们都会诅咒进入炼狱
we're gonna be condemned to purgatory
永远生活在这破玩意儿里
under this thing for all of time.
-永世不得超生 -莱尔 莱尔 冷静点
- Forever, forever, forever. - Lyle, Lyle, Lyle, settle down,
不然我会再把你拷上 听着
or the cuffs are going back on. Look...
这些都是穹顶出现之前得到的
these couldn't have come after the dome came down.
也许我们不知道它将怎样结束
Maybe we don't know how it ends.
你说得对
You're right.
邮政关门了
Postcards stopped.
但她确实每天都写日志
But she did write in the journal every day.
我猜你是这一切的关键也写在日志中
I bet you the key to this is in the journal.
呃 我叔叔来过 在葬礼之后
Uh, my uncle came and picked up
他拿走了她的一堆东西
a bunch of her stuff after the funeral.
她不会想让萨姆拿走她的日志 不可能
She wouldn't want Sam to have her journal. Not him.
-你们到底有什么秘密 -这不重要
- What is it with you guys, anyway? - It doesn't matter.
我们去把日志抢回来
Let's just go get the journal.
-不 不 -你不想了解你妈妈
- Oh, no, no. - You don't want to know about your mother?
还有那个被杀的女孩儿
What about that girl that got killed?
安吉
Angie?
你为什么这么说
Why would you say that?
我很清楚的记得 我坐在门廊看着蔷薇酒吧
I have a real clear view of the Sweetbriar Rose from my porch.
我看到你等她
I've watched you waiting for her
接她下班
to pick her up after her shift.
-很抱歉她去世了 -等等
- I'm really sorry about what happened to her... - Wait.
你觉得我妈把安吉的死也写下来了
You think my mom put Angie's murder in her journal?
哦 谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
丽贝卡让你们来帮忙的吗
Did Rebecca send you to help?
-帮什么忙 -她说有一头猪出问题了
- Help with what? - She said it'd be just the one pig,
但她说得不对
but she was wrong.
是好多头都有问题
There are more.
就今天早上开始的
Just since this morning.
十几头猪都病了
A dozen of them.
把健康的那些隔离
Quarantine the healthy animals.
原来丽贝卡在厨房里搞得是这个名堂
This is what Rebecca was messing around with in her kitchen.
猪瘟就是他们的消除计划
That pig virus is their extermination plan.
是啊 而且她根本不清楚猪瘟有多严重
Yeah, and she doesn't know how strong it is.
我们得在他们释放病毒前找到他们
We've got to find them before they release it.
他们会在哪里释放呢
Where would they do it?
公共场合 交通繁忙的地方
Someplace busy, someplace public.
大吉姆会在蔷薇酒吧召开小镇集会
Big Jim's having a town meeting at the Sweetbriar.
他们应该就是要去那儿
That's where they'll be.
茱莉亚就是带我来了这里 看的迷你穹顶
This is where Julia brought me, to show me the mini-dome.
梅兰妮 你去哪
Melanie, where are you going?
她要去迷你穹顶那儿
She's going to the exact spot where it was.
你还好么
You all right?
发生了什么
What just happened?
我想起来了
I remember.
那天晚上 我和波林 佛多一起
It was night. I came here looking
来这里找粉色星星的坠落之处
for where the pink stars fell with Pauline Verdreaux.
-和朱尼尔的妈妈 -是的
- Junior's mom? - Yes.
萨姆 佛多也在
We were with Sam Verdreaux
还有莱尔 乔密
and Lyle Chumley.
他们是我们的男朋友
They were our boyfriends.
你和萨姆
You and Sam?
我的头要炸开了
My head is exploding.
继续
Hold on.
之后怎么了
And then what happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
这个地点
That spot.
让你找回了你的记忆
It's bringing back your memory.
如果你想对自己的身份了解的更多
If you want to know more about who you are,
就得再站上去
then you have to get back on it.
那是什么
What is it?
看起来像是陨石 正在发光发热呢
Looks like a meteor. It's glowing.
我们去看看
Let's go see.
我们找到了陨石
We found a meteorite.
就在这儿
Right here.
也许我们应该碰碰它
Maybe we're supposed to touch it.
当我们碰到它时 它啪的一声打开了
When we touched it, it... it cracked open.
大家都没事吧 你没事吧
Is everybody okay? You okay?
里面有个蛋
There was an egg inside.
噢 我的天 那是什么
Oh, my God... What is that?
梅兰妮 不要
Melanie, stop.
-梅兰妮 -你在干什么
- Melanie. - What are you doing?
放回去 不要动它
Put it back. Don't do that.
我拿起了它
I took it.
我想保护它
I wanted to protect it.
梅兰妮 把它放回去
Melanie, put it back!
梅兰妮 你要去哪
Melanie! Where are you going?
-梅兰妮 回来 -梅 梅兰妮
- Melanie, come back! - Mel-Melanie!
梅兰妮
Melanie!
萨姆要我把它放回去 但是我没有
Sam told me to put it back, but I wouldn't.
丢掉它 梅兰妮 把它放回去
Drop it, Melanie. Put it back!
你没事吧
Are you ok?
发生了什么 那声音快要了我的命了
What is happening?! The sound is killing me!
我是梅兰妮 克鲁斯
I am Melanie Cross.
我想这里就是我死去的地方
And I think this is where I died.
病毒准备好了么
Is the virus ready?
是的
Yes.
你准备好了么
Are you?
没人告诉过我 做决断者
No one tells you what it's like...
是什么样的感受
...being the one who has to decide.
你被选中
You were chosen
是因为你足够强大 足以做决定
because you're strong enough to do it.
你知道的 我曾经历过这样的考验
You know, I was tested like this before.
怎么了
What happened?
是我的妻子 波林
It was my wife, Pauline.
她病了
She got sick.
她开始
She started...
能看见一些东西 变得偏执妄想 像中了邪一样
seeing things, got paranoid, had these spells.
她得了精神病
She was mentally ill;
那 那不是你的错
that's... that's not your fault.
我知道她需要帮助 所以
I knew she needed help, so...
我找到了一个地方 离这里隔了几个镇子
I found this facility... A few towns away.
她求我 不要把她带去那里
She begged me not to take her there,
并保证她会好起来的
promised she'd get better.
所以我让步了
And I gave in.
没带她去
Didn't make her go.
因为我爱她
'Cause I loved her.
我相信有爱就足够了
I believed that would be enough.
但事实并非如此
But it wasn't.
她自杀了
She took her own life.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
如果我做了那艰难的决定 选择正确的话
If I'd made the tough choice, the right choice...
也许她真会好起来
...maybe she would have gotten better.
也许她现在还活着
Maybe she'd be alive.
这一次我要做对的选择
This time I'll make that choice.
我八岁时 我妈妈去世了
My mother died when I was eight.
她的心脏
Her heart just...
就 就那样停止了
you know... stopped.
我们当时正骑着单车绕过海军基地
We were riding our bikes around the army base,
突然她就
and suddenly she was just...
去世了
gone.
我问我爸爸 为什么
I asked my dad why,
他说 有时候就是没有为什么
and he said, "Sometimes there are no answers."
所以我爱上了科学
And that's why I turned to science.
如果你观察够仔细 那就一定会有答案
If you look hard enough, there is an answer.
你得把它投到水中
You'll need to distribute it in water.
人群多的地方会增加感染的几率
A crowd will increase the rate of infection.
我知道这是哪儿
I know the place.
在1988年的时候
Back in 1988,
你 山姆 波林 还有莱尔
you, Sam, Pauline and Lyle
是最初的四双手
were the original four hands.
你们也找到一颗蛋是吗
And you found an egg, too?
然后某个混账也因此杀了她
And some jackass killed her because of it.
你确定你没看见是谁推你吗
Are you sure you didn't see who pushed you?
肯定不是波林 她当时已经
It wasn't Pauline-- she was...
吓惨了
freaking out.
莱尔当时很愤怒
Lyle was really mad.
所以是山姆
So was Sam.
我只是想保护那颗蛋
I just wanted to protect the egg.
那是什么
What was that?
感觉是一块石头
Feels like a rock.
对啊  外太空飞来的一块石头
Yeah, a rock from outer space.
首字母是MC
Initial's "M.C."
梅勒妮
Melanie...
我想这应该是你的
...I believe this is yours.
如果我已经死了
If I died...
那我是什么
then what am I?
你为什么又会在这儿
And why are you here?
你的尸骨又在哪儿
And where are your bones?
我想山姆 佛多肯定知道答案
I bet Sam Verdreaux could answer those questions.
是的
Yeah.
那天晚上他在场
He was there that night.
如果这一切都是真的
And if all this is true,
那他这几天都已经见到过梅兰妮了
he's seen Melanie in the last couple days.
我的意思是 是他帮茱莉亚救了她的命
I mean, he helped Julia save her life.
你难道会忘记你的前女友吗
Wouldn't you remember your ex-girlfriend?
但是他装得好像完全不认识她似的
But he acts like he never even knew her.
也许他不是在演戏
Maybe it's not an act, though.
也许就是他杀了她
And maybe he's the one who killed her.
不是他就是莱尔
It's either him or Lyle.
但是山姆是爱我的
But Sam loved me.
那他一定在隐瞒着什么
Well, he's hiding something.
嘿  大吉姆
Hey, Big Jim.
我们抓住那些在桥上乱涂乱画的人了
We caught those vandals that were defacing the bridge.
干得好 菲尔 继续保持
Good job, Phil. Keep it up.
吉姆
Jim!
我是想 在开大会之前
I was just, uh, getting something to drink
我想喝点水  怎么
before the big meeting. What's...
谁都别喝水
Nobody drink the water.
吉姆 你需要帮忙吗
Jim, you need anything?
当然  我需要你把这两个人给请出去
Yeah. I need these two escorted out of here.
为什么  这样你就好把致死流感病毒放进水里了吗
Why? So you can dump a deadly flu virus into the drinking water?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你认为你可以决定别人的生死吗
You think you get to control who lives and who dies?
好了 大家 冷静点
All right, everyone, calm down.
我根本不知道这两个人在说些什么
I don't know what these two are talking about...
恩 我到很乐意地告诉大家
Well, I'd be more than happy to tell everybody
-关于你和丽贝卡怎么   -你们是愿意相信
- about how you and Rebecca... - You want to listen
一个每天早上醒来都想着
to someone who wakes up every day
怎么使切斯特磨坊镇变得更好的一个人
trying to make Chester's Mill a better place,
还是愿意相信一个酒鬼和一个
or do you want to believe the town drunk and the town's...
好了 作为绅士有些话我还是不明说了
Well, I'm too much of a gentlemen to say.
搜过你的口袋之后 随便你叫我什么
You can call me whatever you want after you empty your pockets.
我可不需要向你证明什么
I don't got anything to prove to you.
小心点
Be careful with that.
这是什么
What's this?
在哪儿 病毒在哪儿
Where is it? Where's the virus?
什么病毒
What virus?
在丽贝卡手里
Rebecca has it!
我们不应该这么翻我舅舅的东西吧
We shouldn't be going through my uncle's stuff like this.
嘿 如果你妈妈的日记本在这儿
Hey, if your mom's journal's here,
日记本可不是山姆的  那不是他的东西
it doesn't belong to Sam, it's not his stuff.
那是你的
It belongs to you.
只有这样才能带来四骑士
It's the only way to bring forth the Four Horsemen.
好 好 别再鬼扯了
Okay, enough with the Rapture crap.
就是这个 是吗
This is it, right?
嘿 给
Hey, give...
-还给我    -我等这一刻可等了太久了
- give it back. - I've been waiting a long time for that.
结束这一切  和波林在一起
To end it all, to be with Pauline--
里面好多页都没了
and there are pages missing!
在这儿我说了算  莱尔
I'm calling the shots here, Lyle!
-不   -莱尔
- No. - Lyle!
好了
Okay.
你发现了什么
What did you find?
哟 无信仰者突然就寻求开导了啊
Suddenly, the nonbeliever seeks enlightenment.
里面有关于安琪的嘛
Does it say something about Angie?
你为什么不给我看
What don't you want me to see?
那天晚上可能就是你跟着她去了学校
You could have followed her to the school that night.
你杀了安琪 然后利用我逃脱
You killed Angie, and you used me to get out.
我为什么要这么做 啊
Why did I have to do that?! Huh?
很抱歉  孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
但是我永远不会再回去了
I'm out for good now.
欢迎  如果你想的话 你可以点上一支蜡烛
Welcome. You can light a candle if you like.
欢迎
Welcome.
请点上一支蜡烛
Feel free to light a candle.
欢迎
Welcome.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
你好  请坐
Hello. Take a seat, please.
见到你很高兴
Nice to see you.
欢迎  很高兴见到你
Welcome. Good to see you.
一半以上的猪都死了
More than half my pigs are dead.
病毒已经失去控制了
The virus is out of control.
被感染的也越来越多了
More are sick.
这个镇子需要它们为食
The town needed them.
为什么我们要经历这些磨难
Why did this happen to us?
有时并非所有问题都有答案的  汤姆
Sometimes there are no answers, Tom.
要有点信心
Try to have faith
我们一起共同渡过这一关的
that we'll get through this together.
丽贝卡
Rebecca!
离我远点
Get away from me!
你想把我们全杀了
You tried to us all!
茱莉亚  我没有这样做
Julia, I didn't do it.
我没有下毒
I didn't release it.
-离那里远点   -只是检查下我的包
- Get away from there. - J-Just check my purse.
小心点
Carefully.
是良心不安了吗
Crisis of conscience?
我听说病毒变异了
I heard that the virus mutated.
我会尽力而为 但不会不择手段的
I will go as far as I need to, but not farther.
我去让人准备好他的牢房
I'll get the jail cell ready for him.
什么  我什么也没做
What? I didn't do anything.
通向地狱的道路是充满善意的
The road to hell is paved with good intentions.
噢 所以现在你和茱莉亚要拯救小镇 啊
Oh, so now you and Julia are gonna save the town, huh?
当你们没了食物
How are you gonna feed the people
-要怎么养活人们  -反正不能杀了他们
- when you run out of food? - Not by killing them.
是吗   你说起来倒是容易
Oh, yeah? That's easy for you to say.
你从来就没胆子做那些艰难的决定
You never had the balls to make the tough decisions.
当波林开始发疯  然后自杀的时候
When Pauline started losing her mind and killed herself,
你只是把自己封闭了起来
you just ran to the bottle.
现在你投向了茱莉亚
Now you're running off to Julia.
是啊  而你也是像平常一样的胡扯
Yeah, and you're running your mouth off, as usual.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
她要跟你一起作伴蹲监狱了
She's joining you in jail.
是你释放的病毒
You released the virus.
你也打算做这种事
Same thing you were gonna do.
吉姆是肯定不会同意的
Jim would never go through with it.
你太爱这座小镇了
You love this town too much.
所以我才拿了病毒
That's why I took the virus.
你利用我
You used me.
可是 我也做不到
I couldn't do it, either.
但这是你的主意
But it was your idea--
是你说服我让我这样做的
you're the one who talked me into this plan.
当我意识到病毒变异时
When I realized the virus mutated,
我质问了自己  想起了你说过的话
I questioned myself and remembered what you said.
我不能扮演上帝
I can't play God.
知道吗 你们有很多时间
You know what? Plenty of time for you guys
去楼下监狱里面说这些事
to talk about this downstairs.
明天我们会召开镇民大会
Tomorrow we'll have a town meeting
由小镇的人民来决定你们的命运
and the people can decide your fate.
你们打算怎么对付我们
What are you gonna do to us?
我吗 什么也不做
Me? Nothing.
-我希望的是你们能接受审判  -好吧
- My hope is that you'll be put on trial. - Yeah.
让我们共同希望你也带你男友来
Let's hope you bring your boyfriend.
切斯特磨坊镇的人们肯定会十分感兴趣
The people of Chester's Mill will be very interested
芭比对这病毒的说法
in what Barbie has to say about this virus.
为什么
Why's that?
因为他是第一个同意的
'Cause he was the first one on board.
朱尼尔
Junior.
不 他还有呼吸
No, he's still breathing.
嘿 朱尼尔 快醒醒
Hey, Junior, wake up.
朱尼尔  醒醒
Junior, wake up.
我的头
My head.
山姆为什么要这样做
Why'd Sam do this?
不是 是莱尔干的
No, it was Lyle.
莱尔在监狱里面
Lyle's in jail.
不  他没有了  他逃出来了
No, he's not. He's-he's gone.
-他还拿走了我妈妈的日记本   -什么日记本
- He took my mother's journal. - What journal?
放轻松 放松 嘿  莱尔去哪儿了
Easy, easy. Hey. Where did Lyle go?
不  我不知道  但是
No. I don't know, but...
我觉得是他杀了安琪
I think he killed Angie.
也许他也杀了我
Maybe he killed me, too.
乔 过来下 帮我  帮我扶他起来 加把劲
Joe, come on. Help me. Help me get him up. Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
接下来是什么
What's next?
消除计划过后又是什么
What comes after an extermination plot?
嘿  我们撑过了今天
Hey, we made it through the day.
那些制定计划的人进了监狱了
And the guys behind that plan are behind bars.
是啊  大吉姆现在可能正躺在凹凸不平的小床上呢
Yeah. Big Jim's probably lying on a lumpy cot,
想念着他自己舒适的床呢
missing his own bed right about now.
是啊  他今晚可不好过
Yeah. He's had better nights.
我们现在可以好好利用一下人口调查了
Now we can put the census to good use--
想出该如何分配资源
figure out how to share resources.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
我大清早出现在你的门前讲着一大堆疯狂的东西
I showed up on your door at dawn with an insane theory--
你却听得连眼都没眨一下
you didn't blink.
你很能让人信服
You're pretty convincing.
你相信我
You believed me.
这对我来说很有意义
That means something.
等一下
Excuse me.
不
No.
不 茱莉亚  嘿 听着 你得听我给你说
No, Julia. Hey, listen. You got to listen to me.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
你还好吗
You okay?
我会的
I will be.
好吧 那就好
Good. I'm glad.
对不起  我不知道
I'm sorry. I don't know...
我不知道我在想些什么 我会走的
I don't know what I was thinking. I'll go.
-我  -不 不 不
- I... - No, no, no.
请留下
Please stay.
让我们别那么尴尬
Let's not make it weird.
-好的 -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
明天整个小镇都需要答案
The whole town's gonna want answers in the morning.
我需要你的智慧 来告诉我答案是什么
I could really use your help coming up with what those are.
-蜂蜜  -好的 谢谢
- Honey? - Yeah, thanks.